Ajinkya Kathe

Software Engineer

Pune, (+91) 8087186774 ajinkyakathe013@gmail.com

Summary

Two years of experience in Ruby on Rails and hands on experience on Chrome extension, looking to work with esteemed organisation where there is scope for contributing and updating my knowledge and skills for the development of self and the organisation

EXPERIENCE

Cuelogic Technologies, Pune- Software engineer

MAY 2015 - PRESENT

ReplyUp

It is used to automatically send friendly follow-up emails, send from Gmail and track emails if opened and chase your prospects

Team Size - 1

Technologies/Protocol/Software: Ruby, Rails 4, Redis, Sidekiq, Chrome extension, Bootstrap Framework, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL.

- Communicating with client and gathering requirements.
- > Fully responsibility of designing and development of the project including Scheduling, Tracking, Reports, Lead generation model
- Designed and developed Chrome extension
- Used Gmail apis for sending emails
- Worked on Push notifications of gmail
- > Worked on bulk upload of emails sending and scheduling of emails
- Used Stripe as payment gateway
- Writing API's for sharing templates
- Creating Team plans for users and sharing their data

Found.ly

Foundly is a lead generating tool, find prospects information from Linkedin, Quora, Twitter, with the help of Chrome extension.

Team Size - 2

Technologies/Protocol/Software: Ruby, Rails 4, Redis, Sidekiq, Chrome extension, Bootstrap Framework, JavaScript, jQuery, PostgreSQL.

- Full responsibility of designing and development of Templating model
- Created a Rails Engine and used in two apps
- Bug Solving and Providing support to the support team
- ➤ Integration of gmail apis
- > Scrapping of data from sites
- > Worked on Stripe payment gateway
- Worked on Scheduling CRONS

JUNO Software Systems Pvt. Ltd, Pune- Project Trainee

DEC 2014 - MAY 2015

GEMS (Governing Educational Management System)

Is a radically different educational ERP that primarily focuses on education, learning, research and academia. The prime objective of GEMS is to manage, connect and collaborate the key ingredients of an educational institute; which are students and faculties.

Team Size - 20

Technologies/Protocol/Software: Java, Spring MVC, Hibernate,

Bootstrap Framework, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL.

Technology / Tools used

- > Ruby with Rails 4.0
- > PostgresSQL and MYSQL as database, AWS S3 for images
- Sidekiq and Redis for job processing
- > Html, CSS, Jquery, Bootstrap framework for web site
- > Nginx as web server and Passenger as application server
- Github as code repository and Pivotal tracker as bug tracking / estimation tool
- Worked on Firebase for desktop notification
- Operating System Ubuntu
- ➤ ID RubyMine

EDUCATION

Master In Computer Application - 65.00%

Sinhgad Institute of Business Administration & Research, Pune

JUNE 2013 - JUNE 2015 Pune University

Bachelor In Computer Application - 59.50 %

BYK Nashik

JUNE 2010 - JUNE 2013 Pune University

HSC - 64.00%

Bytco College, Nashik

JUNE 2009 - MAY 2010 Pune University

SSC - 62.61%

St Xavier's High School, Nashik

MAY 2008 Pune University

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Quick Learner
- ➤ Hard Working
- ➤ Team Player
- > Self-Disciplined
- > Keen to learn new thing

ACTIVITIES

- Done Game hosting in college festival
- > Student Placement Coordinator in college
- Done training for Road Safety Patrol
- > Participated in Personal Development Camp

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Name: Ajinkya M. Kathe.

Mobile Number: 8087186774.

E-mail Address: ajinkyakathe013@gmail.com

Date of Birth: 13 - Jan - 1993.

Permanent Address: Shree Samartha Krupa bunglow, Lane 2, Uttara Nagar,

Tapovan Link Road, Nashik.

Languages: Marathi (Mother Tongue), English, Hindi.

Marital Status: Single.